<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Effective Altruism Québec</title>
    <link>https://altruismeefficacequebec.org/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Effective Altruism Québec</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://altruismeefficacequebec.org/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://altruismeefficacequebec.org/en/footer/_footer-left/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://altruismeefficacequebec.org/en/footer/_footer-left/</guid>
      <description> More on EA  Intro to effective altruism Video: The Why and How of Effective Altruism Giving 101: The Basics Centre for Effective Altruism  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://altruismeefficacequebec.org/en/footer/_footer-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://altruismeefficacequebec.org/en/footer/_footer-right/</guid>
      <description> Useful links  effectivealtruism.org 80000 Hours GiveWell Centre for Effective Altruism Rethink Charity  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://altruismeefficacequebec.org/en/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://altruismeefficacequebec.org/en/contact/</guid>
      <description>This is the contact page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective Altruism</title>
      <link>https://altruismeefficacequebec.org/en/effective-altruism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://altruismeefficacequebec.org/en/effective-altruism/</guid>
      <description>Effective altruism is a philosophy and social movement that applies evidence and reason to determine the most effective ways to improve the world. Effective altruists aim to consider all causes and actions, and then act in the way that brings about the greatest positive impact. It is this broad evidence-based approach that distinguishes effective altruism from traditional altruism or charity. While a substantial proportion of effective altruists have focused on the nonprofit sector, the philosophy of effective altruism applies much more broadly, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQ</title>
      <link>https://altruismeefficacequebec.org/en/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://altruismeefficacequebec.org/en/faq/</guid>
      <description>Frequently Asked Questions 
So what is effective altruism? The core idea:
Effective altruism is using evidence and analysis to take actions that help others as much as possible.
The world has a lot of horrible problems but we can’t work on them all at once. Our goal is to accomplish the most good for the world with our limited time, energy, and resources.
There is a lot of agreement among people in the movement about what questions we should ask when figuring out what will help others the most.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting involved</title>
      <link>https://altruismeefficacequebec.org/en/get-involved/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://altruismeefficacequebec.org/en/get-involved/</guid>
      <description>Getting involved  Attend our events. Bring friends!
 Follow the Effective Altruism Québec Facebook page. Consider joining the EA Montréal Facebook group, the EA Montŕeal Meetup group, the Altruisme Efficace Ville-de-Québec Facebook group, the EA McGill Facebook group, and the Altruisme Efficace UdeM (Université de Montréal) Facebook group.
 Read a book on the subject.
 Prepare an event, for example a presentation, and get in touch with us to make it happen!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Key Terms</title>
      <link>https://altruismeefficacequebec.org/en/key-terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://altruismeefficacequebec.org/en/key-terms/</guid>
      <description>Key EA Terms 
Core Ideas Effective altruism: Effective altruism (EA) is the name of a growing social movement and an idea – based around using evidence and reason to find the most effective possible ways of doing good in the world. An effective altruist is someone who identifies with and tries to act according to the principles of Effective Altruism.
Cost-effectiveness: The cost-effectiveness of a charitable intervention simply refer to how much good it does with a certain amount of resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organization</title>
      <link>https://altruismeefficacequebec.org/en/organizations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://altruismeefficacequebec.org/en/organizations/</guid>
      <description>Organizations 
AMF: The Against Malaria Foundation (AMF) is a non-profit that funds the distribution of long-lasting insecticidal nets (LLIN) to areas with high incidence of malaria, mostly in Africa. GiveWell has recommended AMF as a top charity several times. As of 2017, GiveWell estimated that it costs AMF about $4.22 to distribute one LLIN and $3,000 per equivalent under-5 year old life saved.
Animal Charity Evaluators investigates the most effective ways of reducing non-human animal suffering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://altruismeefficacequebec.org/en/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://altruismeefficacequebec.org/en/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects If you have a project, or are interested in starting a project, we would be happy to help you. We can give you feedback, give you ideas, help you analyze your project idea in a framework of effective altruism, help you find funding, connect you with other people interested in these ideas, etc. It’s also possible to join an existing project, as well as volunteer or do an internship with Effective Altruism Québec.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading Material</title>
      <link>https://altruismeefficacequebec.org/en/reading-material/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://altruismeefficacequebec.org/en/reading-material/</guid>
      <description>Reading Material 
A lot of material has been developed on how we can go about doing a lot of good. Here is some of the best.
If you like TED talks, watch Peter Singer’s The Why and How of Effective Altruism or check out any of the other TED talks and presentations on effective altruism. The Life You Can Save (Singer’s first book on Effective Altruism) in 3 minutes is also a great watch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team</title>
      <link>https://altruismeefficacequebec.org/en/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://altruismeefficacequebec.org/en/team/</guid>
      <description>Team 
Mati Roy  President and co-founder of Effective Altruism Québec
Website: matiroy.com
Email: contact@matiroy.com
Mati has been part of the LessWrong community for many years. In 2016, Mati has helped create the Macroscope — an intentional community of people interested in rationality and effective altruism. Since then, Mati has been helping with the local effective altruism community. Ze quitted zir programming job in August 2017 in order to devote more time to this project.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>